

PERSONAL

- Name
 Roman Tuomisto
- ★ Address Halkaisijantie 00980 Helsinki
- Phone number +358 504919485
- Email romantuomisto@gmail.com
- Date of birth
 07-03-1985
- LinkedIn

 https://www.linkedin.com/in/romatuomisto-a3780549/

LANGUAGES

*
*

ROMAN TUOMISTO

I am an enthusiastic Full Stack Web application developer, database and UX designer with 3 years of experience.

My experience ranges across several technologies such as NodeJS, Express, MongoDB, React, HTML5, CSS3, SASS, Javascript, JQuery, Bootstrap, Material UI, Semantic UI, PHP, SQL and more. I have a deep interest in understanding how programming languages really work in order to produce best possible result for end user.

I constantly improve my teamwork skills because I find them vital for success.



WORK EXPERIENCE

Mar 2016 - Present

Freelance Full Stack Web Developer

Rolling Records Tmi, Helsinki

Target was to build an E-commerce web app for Rolling Records store. This project was my first big freelance Full Stack project that involved **database planning**, **securing** NodeJS REST + CRUD API endpoints and OOP based **checkout system** that relies on a session and cookies. The application uses third party APIs such as Klarna Checkout and Unifaun (Posti / Itella). Latest update included a **marketplace** where customers can buy and sell their own CD and Vinyl. I also had the chance to setup domain and domain email to this website. Furthermore, I performed Search Engine Optimization and improved site loading speed for the website and made it more responsive.

I worked in cooperation with the CEO of Rolling Records and its staff to build an **admin panel** that they all can easily use. I planned the entire project from scratch by using tools like **Trello**, where I made backlog of requirements and steps.

Stack used in this app: NodeJS + ExpressJS, MongoDB on the backend & EJS, Jquery, Bootstrap, SASS on the frontend.

www.rollingrecords.fi

Oct 2017 - Jul 2019

Freelance Full Stack Web Developer

Venpo Energia Oy, Helsinki

The goal was to build two websites that Venpo Energia needed for their online operations. We agreed that I build two websites, one being a presentational **static website** (https://www.venpoenergia.fi) while the other is a **dynamic web app**that has a time booking system and a possibility to search and filter tyres by manufacturer, size and cartype (https://klaukkalanrengas.fi).

The booking system that we planned together with the CEOexceeded expectations. It can generate times for a whole month at a time and for a whole year ahead. On UI side the interaction with its calendar is designed to be smooth and easy for customers to use on various different devices.

Stack used in this app: NodeJS + ExpressJS, MongoDB on the backend & EJS, Jquery, Semantic UI, CSS3 on the frontend.

https://klaukkalanrengas.fi & https://www.venpoenergia.fi

Jun 2012 - Jul 2019

Shift Manager & Salesperson

Lidl Suomi, Helsinki

In Lidl Ky I was able to develop my skills as a shift manager by organizing

work between different kinds of people. I learned to work fast and organized in order to set an example for new colleagues. As a sales person I frequently received positive feedback from customers for assisting them in finding the right products.

Sep 2011 - Nov 2011

If P&C Insurance, Helsinki

Insurange Agent

As IF's Insurance agent I was able to get into the complex world of insurances, I found insurances being interesting products to sell and work with. My main goal was to sell insurances to customers by calling them. In order to introduce insurances to customers I participated in a schooling. The schooling included details of different kinds of insurances (car, home, health, etc.) and insurance law that defines responsibilities of an insurance company.

2006 - 2011

Trainee Experience

Various employers

- Customer Servise Representative at Staffpoint Oy.
- Customer Servise Representative at Barona Oy.
- Customer Servise Representative Jysk Oy.
- Industry worker Vallilan sahatavara AB
- Roof Frame builder Martinniemi Timber Oy



EDUCATION AND QUALIFICATIONS

Dec 2012

Bachelor of Business Administration

Haaga-Helia ammattikorkeakoulu, Porvoo

- Major: Accounting and financial administration
- Minors: Marketing and CRM

May 2009

Vocational Qualification in Business and Administration Helsinki Business College, Helsinki

Heisiliki busilless College, Heisiliki

 $\star\star\star\star\star$

Major: Accounting and financial administration
 Minors: Marketing and CRM



SKILLS

Tiimityöskentelijä

Kommunikointitaidot

NodeJS, MongoDB, ReactJS,

HTML5, CSS3 + SASS

MySQL, PHP, Python, Docker,
Redis...

Linux, MacOS, Windows,
Debian, NGINX, APACHE

★★★★★

Adobe Photoshop